{
  "computer_papers": [
    {
      "year": 2022,
      "subject": "Computer",
      "candidates": "For Fresh Candidates of 2022",
      "max_marks": 60,
      "time": "3 Hours",
      "sections": [
        {
          "name": "Section A - Multiple Choice Questions",
          "marks": 24,
          "instructions": [
            "Attempt all the Questions of this Section",
            "Do not copy down the part questions. Write only the answer against the proper number of the Question and its part according to the question Paper",
            "Each question carries 1 Mark"
          ],
          "questions": [
            {
              "number": "i",
              "question": "The type of function which is the part of a computer language is known as:",
              "options": ["user-define function", "library function", "sub-program", "None of these"],
              "correct_answer": "library function"
            },
            {
              "number": "ii",
              "question": "The process of converting source code into object code is known as:",
              "options": ["Compiling", "Executing", "Linking", "Saving"],
              "correct_answer": "Compiling"
            },
            {
              "number": "iii",
              "question": "An inverter is:",
              "options": ["OR", "AND", "NOT", "none of these"],
              "correct_answer": "NOT"
            },
            {
              "number": "iv",
              "question": "Step by step solution of a problem in simple language is called:",
              "options": ["Problem solving", "Algorithm", "Flowchart", "Data Structure"],
              "correct_answer": "Algorithm"
            },
            {
              "number": "v",
              "question": "The looks of sprite can be changed by using:",
              "options": ["backdrop tab", "costume tab", "script tab", "control tab"],
              "correct_answer": "costume tab"
            },
            {
              "number": "vi",
              "question": "The type of data that is used for decimal point value is:",
              "options": ["Int", "char", "boot", "float"],
              "correct_answer": "float"
            },
            {
              "number": "vii",
              "question": "The parts of switch statements are \"case\" and:",
              "options": ["have", "if", "default", "for"],
              "correct_answer": "default"
            },
            {
              "number": "viii",
              "question": "Loop within a loop is called:",
              "options": ["inner", "outer", "enclosed", "nested"],
              "correct_answer": "nested"
            },
            {
              "number": "ix",
              "question": "In a flowchart, an arrow represents:",
              "options": ["decision making", "start", "data flow", "stop"],
              "correct_answer": "data flow"
            },
            {
              "number": "x",
              "question": "\"!=\" operator belongs to which type of operator?",
              "options": ["Arithmetic", "Logical", "Relational", "None of these"],
              "correct_answer": "Relational"
            },
            {
              "number": "xi",
              "question": "Which of the following needs pressing \"Enter key\" from keyboard?",
              "options": ["getch()", "getche()", "getchar()", "gets()"],
              "correct_answer": "gets()"
            },
            {
              "number": "xii",
              "question": "In Boolean Algebra. A.A = :",
              "options": ["0", "1", "A", "Ā"],
              "correct_answer": "A"
            },
            {
              "number": "xiii",
              "question": "Which operator is used for input stream from the following:",
              "options": [">", "<", ">>", "<<"],
              "correct_answer": ">>"
            },
            {
              "number": "xiv",
              "question": "The Boolean expression of NOR gate two variables is:",
              "options": ["A + B", "Ā + B", "Ā + B", "A . B"],
              "correct_answer": "Ā + B"
            },
            {
              "number": "xv",
              "question": "To send value, to the calling function we use:",
              "options": ["throw statement", "send statement", "return statement", "back statement"],
              "correct_answer": "return statement"
            },
            {
              "number": "xvi",
              "question": "The number of bytes used by \"int\" type in C++ is:",
              "options": ["2", "4", "8", "1"],
              "correct_answer": "4"
            },
            {
              "number": "xvii",
              "question": "C++ statement ends at:",
              "options": [".", ";", ":", ","],
              "correct_answer": ";"
            },
            {
              "number": "xviii",
              "question": "In scratch, the character which moves on the stage is called a:",
              "options": ["Sprite", "command", "script", "event"],
              "correct_answer": "Sprite"
            },
            {
              "number": "xix",
              "question": "Which of the following operator works only with integer value?",
              "options": ["/", "%", "+", "*"],
              "correct_answer": "%"
            },
            {
              "number": "xx",
              "question": "The process of given variable, its starting value is called:",
              "options": ["declaring", "naming", "Initializing", "none of these"],
              "correct_answer": "Initializing"
            },
            {
              "number": "xxi",
              "question": "The universal gate is:",
              "options": ["NAND Gate", "AND Gate", "OR Gate", "None of these"],
              "correct_answer": "NAND Gate"
            },
            {
              "number": "xxii",
              "question": "The word \"prototype\" means:",
              "options": ["Declaration", "Calling", "Definition", "None of these"],
              "correct_answer": "Declaration"
            },
            {
              "number": "xxiii",
              "question": "All errors, detected by a user are:",
              "options": ["syntax errors", "run time errors", "logical errors", "none of these"],
              "correct_answer": "logical errors"
            },
            {
              "number": "xxiv",
              "question": "\"break\" statement is used with:",
              "options": ["if", "switch", "for", "while"],
              "correct_answer": "switch"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "name": "Section B - Short Answer Questions",
          "marks": 24,
          "instructions": [
            "Attempt any EIGHT Questions from this section",
            "All questions carry equal marks"
          ],
          "questions": [
            {
              "number": 2,
              "question": "What is Computer Program?"
            },
            {
              "number": 3,
              "question": "Write down the purposes of any two statements: (i) if-else (ii) return (iii) exit () (iv) continue"
            },
            {
              "number": 4,
              "question": "Why do we use Boolean Algebra?"
            },
            {
              "number": 5,
              "question": "Differentiate between Arithmetic operators and relational operators."
            },
            {
              "number": 6,
              "question": "Why is there need of index in an array?"
            },
            {
              "number": 7,
              "question": "Write down any three rules of naming variable in C++."
            },
            {
              "number": 8,
              "question": "Write the uses of any three escape sequences:"
            },
            {
              "number": 9,
              "question": "Explain the purpose of \"default\" in C++."
            },
            {
              "number": 10,
              "question": "What are strings in C++?"
            },
            {
              "number": 11,
              "question": "Write the functions of \"for loop\"."
            },
            {
              "number": 12,
              "question": "Explain increment operator (++) and write the name of two ways of its usage."
            },
            {
              "number": 13,
              "question": "Describe comment statement. How many types of comment statement are used in C++?"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "name": "Section C - Detailed Answer Questions",
          "marks": 12,
          "instructions": [
            "Attempt any TWO (2) questions from this section",
            "Each question carries SIX (06) marks"
          ],
          "questions": [
            {
              "number": 14,
              "question": "Write any three steps of problem solving."
            },
            {
              "number": 15,
              "question": "Differentiate between constant and variable."
            },
            {
              "number": 16,
              "question": "Describe the following translators: (i) Compiler (ii) Interpreter (iii) Assembler"
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}